[ Noise ]
Hello everyone
Well
I am in the
the tail means that I have never coded a line
the code since my
you love me therefore I am rather than products therefore
I am a product consultant at Zenika and
well after
over and over again from Jul here I am
[ Noise ]
no and so
I'm going to talk to you about product management, to whom the product speaks
Well
I did well to
[ Noise ]
really the goal to really give you a presentation
Product management summary 10 minutes
I will of course teach you everything and
say show that
Well
the developers also have a recreate
in this product management approach
what is product management product management is an approach to creation and innovation
put me centered and directed on the product there you will tell me
what is the product Eva the product
bitch it can be a service or a good that meets a need
specific to one or more users
so actually
all you develop in itself is products
so what
really consists
Well
This is what we find
In fact
put in the center really 3
you love me what are business marketing knowledge
In fact
Well
we have a product the objective is to sell how we are going to sell it to whom we are addressing
to which market
turnover we plan to make how we are going to sell the
country with what pricing or
others so in fact
there is all this thinking there
there is the design part how we do it we will
pose an experience to users so that
how he still wants to use it back
bring back user retention
and to the
Haiti part
Well
This is really the realization
delivery comment on what is - what are we going to use
to be able to set it up is available
of the target customer
really it's a bit of a whole
and so in fact
And
L
' together
Well
they are
You're going to tell me that on the developer side it's very
but precisely
I think there is an interest in that
person working on a product understands at least
the C3 large areas and it touches a little
in a way therefore
the concept of product management is a sentence
that I use a lot and that I often put I say that it is often the most important sentence
come when I do training for management it is
the concept will be validated by proof as quickly as possible
your work on the right product so
what does it mean validated by proof
In fact
It is that we
good I had directors who said
Well here it is
we will do this functionality
it's gonna be awesome
in general
it's not really proof
SO
it's good it's more of an opinion
and in fact
it's necessary
validate this opinion if you need to
East
- what there will really be of having the value of the impact for the
radiator upstream and
In fact
validate by proof it can be
before development but also after development
you are awesome you have developed what is - which proves that after this feature
I will develop and really great what you are basing it on
as soon as possible
Well
it's simply the fact
if we have ideas and we want to be able to
at what time are the most users? Well if we are the first
more likely to acquire them and
also well
that some us
change quickly
and also well
it allows the faster we do it, the more we validate
quickly the test and that we work on the right product and there you go
yesterday what is the good product and well it's a bit really
you are of some use to the three axes that we saw previously
It's really about making sure that we're responding to the need for a real problem.
why it is important because
In fact
if we solve
problem well there will be none easily no use
the fact
that
Well
there is room on the market here
there may be competition, the competition which also already responds very well
if we want to deliver a product almost
versatile
we try there is little chance that it will succeed the fact
for the company the objective of the company is
It's about making money, so here are the investments that will
well
you there will be a return on investment and also
the super important point that it is technically feasible
so there
- above
what is the approach a little bit of
overall protection Seba for
make sure of the previous sentence
every time it is better to start on a product to have a vision
drink
we want to go in the direction of Cape Town, it's
In fact
to bring on board the people who work on the product
SO
television is not particularly
very very clear and that's a bit why we
but
after that it is how we will reach this vision therefore
put the strategy
actually there
10 is really all we are going to put in place for
turn off the vision so understand the market
how to master your sound product the functional is -
This
that
come knowingly the ex
what do we offer and also collect the different feedback and
All
For
listen rotate if necessary for different features
Who
results from it
In fact
This is the remark what is also
Well
the camp will deliver it
and also
a governance aspect but here it is
It is all the stakeholders who will be able to interact to make
advance the product I will go now
a little more in detail for example on the vision
often something you can touch
job often it often makes the difference
It's just having a vision and not a plan
There is this example of Martin Luther King for civil rights.
bathrobe in the United States he didn't say we're going soon
no actually
he really has
you are right that all these people can demonstrate
and have a real weight which has allowed them to access the order
This famous I have a dream speech which really allowed
to take on a large number of people
be black himself - black and who wished
give me equality of people so really that will be the why
the reason for being a little of the product it can be something
It's very short but really specific and not transposable, that means
escape it only belongs to this product it can not use for another product
And
This really helps to explain the why
small aside I don't know if you know this face
Simone Sinex's spear on
please why it is important
In fact
to bring some why for
people who work in the company
Well
simply
easier to move forward with them
I will move forward because I only have left
10 minutes on vision
we have the vision and then
Well
it will be
destroy this product and well we will go through big ones
one of which you know well and one perhaps a little less well which is the Discovery
how what are we going to do
This
product what are we going to deliver and
how do we make sure that we will be able to do it?
to give impact and that the product is a product
This is the stage of Discovery and we will define
responds to user issues with solutions that will
so being the delivery will be how we will deliver our solutions
if developers intervene but on Discovery developers can also
better understand customer expectations and intervene
how to also do inter participate in user interviews to see
how the product is used
it m '
in
come now
parenthesis so in fact
Product management is really a holistic approach
with different aspects which are business design
steak for me I define it more it is not a work framework
It's more of a set of practices that we can use
For
of the success of our product a
really this approach allows to lead the whole thing early
investment therefore the fact of validating the hypotheses before development
so this
This is the Discovery stage that I just told you about to reduce precisely
the vision that allows to give
direction and
A
also sense the products and embark the whole
and the people involved in the product too
It is also important to focus on the impact of functions
functionality delivered and not just on functionality and
It is very important to validate the impact
Valerie after it is delivered and the last one
No, it's just that
In fact
Developers have a crucial role
creation of these products
actually going actually
to touch
for example in
Discovery participant ensure
product forecast - are we still consistent with this vision or not?
so there are a lot of things that can be seen on
product management and I think the Daves have a role there too
And
that will be all it's 10 minutes it's very short
and here it is
This is a small introduction but with pleasure for
in
talk after
[ Noise ]